China's approach to fight the coronavirus is practicing
our belief that "humanity is a community of shared future".
You are working on the front line.
How do you feel?
We only have one role on the front line.
We are the fighters.
Why would Tedros Adhanom speak out for China?
Experts like him felt that China has done more than the
general requirement for epidemic prevention.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie
微信公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
(Producing Partner: Guan Video)
Hello everyone, welcome to China Now.
While we are still challenged by the
2019 novel coronavirus (COVID-19),
we see that Hubei Province is coming to the final stage of the battle
and the number of confirmed cases in
other regions continues to go down.
We are seeing the light at the end of the tunnel.
This couldn't have been possible without
the effort made by all the industries
and the cooperation from all the people.
Just as the director general of WHO
Tedros Adhanom has said,
"The high speed and massive scale of
China's moves are rarely seen in the world."
"The steps China has taken to contain the outbreak at
its source appear to have bought the world time."
Today, we are here to discuss and compare
how China and other countries respond to disease outbreaks.
We will also talk about how different
countries develop their public health systems.
We have two guests today.
Professor Zhang Weiwei, Director of
the China Institute of Fudan University.
Professor Cai Yuyang, Associate Professor at
School of Public Health of Shanghai Jiao Tong University.
This is a special episode where
we don't have a live audience.
We will begin with a keynote speech from Professor Zhang
and then have a roundtable discussion with our guests.
Professor Zhang, please.
The sudden outbreak of the disease is a disaster for everyone.
International unity and collective response
is "the right path for humanity to follow".
However, some western media are gloating about the situation
and taking this chance to spread their fallacies.
An American scholar, in his cold-war mindset,
published "China Is the Real Sick Man of Asia"
on Wall Street Journal.
The cover page of Courrier Picard says
"Alerte Jaune" [Yellow Alert],
implying this is a "yellow disaster".
US Secretary of Commerce Wilbur Ross
openly said to the press that
the coronavirus could help the United States
bring back jobs and manufacturing.
All these views immediately caused
an uproar in the international press.
There have been many insightful
protests and rebuttal home and abroad.
The majority do not tolerate such tramples on
the bottom line of human civilization.
In terms of economy,
Paul Krugman, recipient of the
Nobel Memorial Prize in Economic Sciences,
also criticized Wilbur Ross, saying that
the coronavirus isn’t good for America.
"Even if it doesn’t kill you, it might kill your job."
He said when SARS broke out in China in 2003,
China only accounted for 8% of global manufacturing.
Today, however, China accounts for a quarter of global manufacturing.
If the virus disrupts Chinese production,
America's economy will be seriously inflicted.
He said that was Wilbur Ross’s "boneheaded remarks".
Today we live in a world of global value chains.
The failure of one link will fail all.
Fortune Magazine posted that the manufacturing of
almost all consumer electronics depends on China.
When the iPhone manufacturers in China delayed return of workers,
it shaved US$ 27 billion off Apple's stock market value.
Hubei Province is a key supplier for global auto parts.
Because of the epidemic, the global
auto industry is facing factory shutdowns.
It halts production of Nissan and Hyundai Korea
due to the low supply of auto parts.
Nearly a third of German companies encountered supply shortage
and even the drug supply in the U.S. has been impacted.
Most of the antibiotics used in the United States come from China.
Insulin, antidepressants, blood thinners, etc.
directly or indirectly rely on China's supply chain.
Financial Times believed that many countries would
run out of drugs if China failed to resume production.
Some Americans advocacy groups are trying to decouple
the US economy from China amid the COVID-19 outbreak.
That's easier said than done.
China's opening up has embedded our
economy in the world economic system.
China has long been a key link in the
industry chain of global manufacturing.
Although the production lines of multinational
companies have also moved out of China in the past few years,
most of them are short production lines
such as shoe and clothing production.
Economies like China with internationally
complete and complex industrial chain are rare.
Moreover, China is the world’s largest consumer market.
I believe that as long as the epidemic ends in a short
period of time, which we are hopeful about,
China’s position in the global value chain will not be shaken.
I also believe that China will do well in defending our economy.
While most countries are supportive of
China’s disease control measures,
some in America accused China's measures
being violations of human rights.
James Hodge, Director of the Center for Public Health
Law and Policy at Arizona State University,
said locking down cities in China is a human-rights violation.
There are also American scholars calling for attention to
the so-called "dark side" of China's quarantine.
The New York Times published "Coronavirus Crisis
Shows China's Governance Failure".
This even made the Singapore PM's wife, Ho Ching to voice on social media
“What about the influenza B deaths in the USA?”
The U.S. Centers for Disease Control reported that
from 1 Oct 2019 to 25 Jan 2020,
less than three months,
the flu has caused at least 19 million infections,
10 thousand deaths, including at least 68 children.
Some western media have been banging the drum
and that proves what I've said a lot on China Now —
that is, there are still people holding on to the bigotry
that everything China does is wrong.
"It's a human right violation if you control the disease,
and a governance failure if it's out of control."
Our conclusion is very simple—just ignore them.
Just as Mr. Lu Xun said, "Don't even bother to roll your eyes."
Do what we ought to do.
Frankly speaking, the Western systems would not
be able to cope with such an outbreak.
You can look at how Australia and California
responded to forest fires last year,
how the United States responded to Hurricane Katrina in 2005,
and the 2009 H1N1 pandemic.
And compare them to how China responded to
2008 Sichuan earthquake and the 2019 coronavirus.
China has taken decisive response measures this time
and achieved significant results.
We won the understanding and support
of most countries in the world.
Wuhan City launched over 10 shelter hospitals
to treat mild coronavirus cases
but rumors in the West call them "concentration camps".
As the patients in the shelter hospitals started to
do square dance, Baduanjin qigong, Tai Chi, and radio calisthenics,
which were impressive to look at,
and as more and more people were discharged,
the rumor soon became self-defeating.
The WHO Executive Board held a meeting on Feb 12 in Geneva,
a European journalist asked the WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom
why he kept praising China and if the
Chinese government asked him to do that.
Tedros Adhanom said,
"We don't need to say anything to please anyone."
He said the purposes of acknowledging some countries were
one, to encourage these countries to continue their policies
and two, to encourage other countries to learn from them.
He also said almost all member states
praised China for what it did at the board meeting,
and the reason is that China took action
massively at the epicenter Wuhan City.
"The shutdown of Wuhan City helped prevent cases from
being exported to other provinces and the rest of the world."
"So what's wrong acknowledging it?"
"China is setting a new standard for outbreak response."
We might as well compare with the US
response to the 2009 H1N1 epidemic.
In late March 2009, H1N1 flu broke out in California and Mexico.
The response of the United States was not slow.
The US found the first sample on April 15,
reported to WHO on April 18,
started to develop vaccine on April 21,
and disclosed [information] to the public on April 23.
April 25, which is 10 days after, the WHO declared
the H1N1 outbreak a "public health emergency of international concern",
and it gradually rose to the highest level of phase 6 in June.
On April 26, the US government also
declared a public health emergency
and began to release strategic reserves in response to the emergency.
Regretfully, their prevention and control measures
did not produce much effect in general.
The epidemic was not contained and spread rapidly.
After three months, the WHO stopped asking
the member states to report the actual numbers.
They had to use whatever statistics was available.
Six months after the outbreak, President Obama
declared H1N1 a national emergency
but the outbreak was already out of control.
It was not contained until the turn of
the spring and summer of the next year.
There was no accurate data in the end.
The CDC could only use model estimation to understand the situation.
From 12 April 2009 to 10 April 2010,
it was estimated 60.8 million people were infected,
which was 1/5 of the US population.
274,000 were hospitalized and 12,469 died,
which is 4.5% of the hospitalized cases.
If we compare this to China,
we should multiply these numbers by four because
China's population is over four times the America's.
That would be about 250 million people infected,
which is over 10 times the Shanghai population.
1.1 million people would have been hospitalized,
and 50,000 would have died.
In addition, because no measures were taken to
prevent the international spread of H1N1,
it had spread to 214 countries and regions by the end of 2012,
killing an estimated 284,500 people worldwide.
By any standard, America's response to H1N1 was very unsuccessful.
Here's probably why.
First, public health resources in many states could not
cope with such a large-scale outbreak,
and the federal government's ability to
coordinate the states was seriously insufficient.
Second, America experienced the worst
post-WW2 financial crisis in 2008.
When companies were shutting down and employees were laid off,
the government did not have enough
financial resources to cope with a sudden outbreak.
The production of American vaccine companies
also fell far short of the targets.
Third, the US government and media
told the public that H1N1 had low mortality rate,
which made people less vigilant.
Fourth, America had a serious lack of international responsibility.
The US government's approach to
this pandemic was, roughly speaking,
publish alerts, provide conveniences,
and then it's all on you.
It is the responsibility of individuals
to take precautionary measures.
Go to the hospital if you need to, but good luck on the treatment.
It also depends on how rich you are.
As for whether H1N1 would spread to
the entire world, it was not their concern.
If anyone was unsatisfied with the US government or hospitals,
they could always sue them.
But the possibility of winning was very low, and they
might have to pay the expensive attorneys themselves.
The differences in China and America's disease response
come from the differences in our political systems.
America's democratic system is, after all, a procedural democracy.
The job is done as long as the
government does not violate the procedures.
They can elect a new government
and the new government will operate the same way.
This is the design of their institution.
Of course, America is very good at one thing,
that is, using capital to control mainstream media.
They are good at creating topics and shifting focus to
"make big problems small, and small problems no problems at all".
This is eventually at the expense of
ordinary people instead of the rich.
Many American netizens believe that
American media's hype over COVID-19 in China
is largely aiming to divert the attention to the weak
government control of the concurrent flu in America.
Frankly, if the US cannot learn from its
failed response to the H1N1 outbreak,
we cannot imagine what would happen if a more deadly
disease or natural disaster happened in America.
China's political system is oriented in substantive democracy.
The Chinese party and government system
is responsible for the entire nation and its continuation.
In economic terms, this is a government with "unlimited liability".
The Chinese nation shares the cultural heritage of
"When one is in trouble, aid will come from eight directions."
The Communist Party of China has the political
philosophy of "putting people's lives above all else",
and has strong capacities to organize, mobilize, and coordinate.
The Chinese people feel strongly about
the identity between nation and family.
Our unity builds the fort to fight the disease.
We can be called to the united action of "staying home".
"We bore the virus to death."
The Chinese army has the spirit of "Never yield, not even to death."
The China Model is characterized by a
multi-pronged approach and mutual cooperation.
From the many medical professionals in public hospitals
and on the front line, to countless hard-working staffers and volunteers;
From large state-owned enterprises in electricity,
telecommunications, grain and oil, air transportation,
to large private companies like Huawei, Alibaba, Tencent, JD.
We all made concerted efforts towards the “defensive
war” and the “all-citizen war” against COVID-19.
Nothing can rival or defeat such a nation, such a party,
such a people, such an army, and such a model.
China and its political system shoulder this
responsibility for its people and the world
at the sacrifice of a period of economic downturn.
The WHO Director General was impressed that
China has confined 99% of the cases within its borders
[the video was published on Feb 24].
This creates a valuable window for the international
communities to jointly respond to the epidemic,
and also sets a new benchmark for global epidemic prevention.
In this sense, China's anti-epidemic model is a practice
of “building a community of shared future for humanity”.
This is distinctly different from the US mindsets of “America First”,
radical individualism, "dumping problems
on neighbors”, and “I win you lose”.
In the short term, the Chinese model means that China
alone will bear more responsibilities and costs.
However, the Chinese people believe
"All beneath Heaven belongs to the public" [Confucius]
and "A just cause attracts much support;
an unjust one finds little" [Mencius].
China is advancing an anti-pandemic model for the world,
and will win more friends and broader common interests.
When the Asian financial crisis began in 1997, many countries
were racing to devalue their currencies to shift the crisis.
China acted as a responsible big country and insisted on
the stability of the RMB exchange rates,
which ultimately won us more friends
and broader common interests.
Russian political scholar [Sergey Alexandrovich] Markov
said that China’s performance proves itself a great country.
"It took the blow alone and protected the world."
China demonstrated that it is qualified to be a superpower,
and with this superpower we will step out of the
epidemic and significantly grow in soft power.
I read an article in the Financial Times by
South African strategist Michael Power,
"Would another government have done better than China’s? "
He was indignant that western governments are
criticizing China's response to the coronavirus.
He wrote [quoted from the original article]
We should not forget what happened nearly 40 years ago
after Dr Jim Curran’s team first detected
the AIDS virus in San Francisco.
Curran published an article in the June 1981
to alarm American and international communities
about this deadly infectious disease.
In 1983, French virologist Dr Luc Montagnier
identified and isolated the virus,
but the Reagan administration dismissed a journalist’s
question and openly called it the “gay plague”.
By then, 800 people had died.
Not until September 17 1985, after 12,000 American
deaths, did President Reagan use the word “AIDS”.
China’s president Xi Jinping did not wait more than
four years to say the word “coronavirus”.
Far less than four weeks in fact. [quote ends]
He laments that if the US government
had not overlooked AIDS,
it would have greatly reduced the disaster on humanity.
As we know, as of 2018, more than 74.9 million people
worldwide were infected with HIV,
of which 32 million people have left the world forever.
Here is a memory I'd like to share with you
On April 15, 1987, Chinese leader Deng Xiaoping met with former
Tanzanian President Julius Nyerere who was visiting China.
I worked as their interpreter and translated their discussion on AIDS.
Deng Xiaoping said with certainty, "The US has the most
AIDS cases, and drug injection is a major reason.”
He then said," We are now trying to use
Chinese herbal medicine to treat AIDS."
Nyerere said that, “For Tanzania, the biggest disease
is not AIDS, but malaria.”
At that time, Nyerere's judgment might be correct,
but with hindsight, he underestimated the
possibility of an AIDS pandemic in Africa.
In the 1990s, in African countries including Botswana,
South Africa, Tanzania, Mozambique, and Swaziland,
AIDS became the number one local killer.
One third of adults in some countries were HIV-positive.
In Swaziland, the coffin industry was
once the fastest growing industry.
That day, Deng Xiaoping and President Nyerere also
discussed China-Africa cooperation
on treating malaria and AIDS with
integrated Chinese and Western medicine.
Deng Xiaoping told him that during the Chinese Agrarian Revolution,
we fought without medicine and doctors, and many
were treated by Chinese herbal medicine.
We can learn two things from this story.
First, from China’s paramount leader to the general public,
everyone agrees that infectious diseases
are the common enemy of humanity,
and all countries must respond together with sincerity.
The human history through smallpox, plague, leprosy,
malaria and many other epidemics
shows us that no country can come out of them unscathed,
and the only right path for humanity is a community of shared futured.
Second, in the face of evolving viruses,
we must explore the integration of traditional
Chinese medicine (TCM) and western medicine.
TCM and western medicine both have their own
strengths and can complement each other.
The fight against coronavirus has
witnessed encouraging effects of TCM.
I hope that our society will value TCM more
and attach more importance to the
integration of Chinese and Western medicine.
It will work, and it should be a valuable contribution
of the Chinese civilization to humanity.
We’ve been seeing signs that indicate the dark clouds
of the epidemic will soon pass,
and the light of the dawn is breaking.
We will see the shine of the rainbow after the storm.
Let us be patient as we wait for tomorrow. Thank you.
Translators: Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie
微信公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Professor Zhang mentioned international comments on
China's response to the coronaviru
and the pressure on China to prevent the spread
of the disease to the rest of the world.
We are under a lot of pressure and many
have been working under this pressure.
Before we open up the Q&A session, I will
connect with an engineer on the front line.
His name is Wang Hongbin, and he is
installing CT equipment in Wuhan City.
- Hello, Hongbin.
- Hello.
Hello, Hongbin, thanks for joining us.
Where are you in Wuhan now?
I'm at the Optics Valley “Cabin Hospital”.
Are you installing CT equipment for the cabin hospital?
Yes, we are testing the devices.
Can you tell us about the process from being informed
to starting work on the front line?
Not many engineers were available and
Wuhan needed a lot of support.
So I thought, as a member of the
Communist Party, I must sign up.
I booked the flight for Jan 27 [the third day of the
Chinese New Year holiday] from Xinjiang to Shanghai.
As all public travel to Wuhan were
suspended including rail and flights,
our company hired a minibus to drive the 6 of us to Wuhan.
The ride was about 30 hours.
Your experience is probably the epitome of many front-line workers.
I understand that you have been working in Wuhan
for more than 20 days since you arrived.
You probably have already installed many devices.
But I'd like to ask how the experience is different and what are the challenges.
Generally speaking, buildings have been completely constructed
with AC and other systems in place
before we install medical devices.
But this project has a very tight timeline.
At Huoshenshan Hospital for example, the construction
of the entire hospital was about ten days,
and we only had about 48 hours to go in.
There were thousands of construction workers on site,
and it was a very dusty environment.
I had never worked in such an environment before.
There was no machine room and no shielding walls.
They built walls and radiation protection as we installed the devices.
But everyone was still racing against time
despite the difficult environment.
We noticed that Hongbin is wearing protective gear as
they must protect themselves on the front line.
But it makes the installation and testing work
very difficult wearing protective clothing.
I understand your time is very valuable working
on the front line, and I just have one last question.
How do you feel about this special task?
I was very nervous and unsure when I first arrived in Wuhan,
but I feel touched by the city as I work here.
When we were working at a cabin hospital,
we were less than 3 meters away from the aisle
where the patients went to bathrooms.
One night when we were working outside, a patient
walked by and asked us how the installation was going.
We said it should be done soon and the device
would be available in the afternoon.
He said, “You worked so hard. Working overnight
to make the devices available in less than a day."
"You guys are great."
I was very touched by his words.
I felt very proud to be able to contribute my effort on the front line.
(Thank you ...)
People who work here all have different roles in life.
We are children, parents, or spouses.
But on the front line, we have only one role — the fighters.
We can only keep going, there’s no turning back.
No matter how difficult it is, we will go forward.
Thank you, thank you Hongbin.
Victory awaits you. I'd like to send my
regards to you and your coworkers.
You’ve all worked hard! Please take care
of yourselves as you fight until victory.
Thank you.
Thank you, we will.
I was very touched during the call.
He is the epitome of the many frontline workers.
The numerous medical workers, police, and community personnel.
We may have been seeing them around,
and there are also many invisible workers
just like Wang Hongbin and his colleagues.
They charged to the front in disregard of “life and death”,
“fame and fortune”, and “gain and loss”.
They push the situation to change for the better,
and their work brings us the light of hope.
We must never take their work for granted.
In previous episodes, Professor Zhang, you have often said
the Chinese people have a sense of
“identity between nation and family”.
How do you feel after the call?
I’m very touched as well.
There were innumerable people who traveled in the reverse
direction towards the center of the national emergency.
Medical workers, PLA soldiers, engineers,
and volunteers rushed to Hubei one batch after another.
I was in Davos, Switzerland on January 24th and 25th.
Local Chinese expats have bought all the masks to send back home.
Chinese expats have a sense of “identity between nation and family”.
I watched an interview of a post-90s nurse.
She spoke very touchingly.
She said, “You protected us post-90s during SARS in
2003. Now it is time for us to take the responsibility.”
This is their sense of “identity between nation and family”.
We have witnessed the hard work of our front-line
medical workers, which is very rare around the world.
It is very difficult for other countries to support
such a campaign under their systems.
In my opinion, this is in the essence of the Chinese civilization,
"I will go despite the opposition of thousands.” [Mencius]
You said it might be difficult for other countries
to support a war-like movement against the disease.
Can you elaborate on that?
For example, Professor Zhang talked about
H1N1 in the United States in 2009.
They had advanced technology to take response in the early stages,
and vaccine was developed relatively quickly.
But it was difficult to achieve effective isolation in the [social] system.
They only provided advice and guidance.
There was no control over how people enforced them,
which lead to the global spread of H1N1.
So what were the specific measures taken by local governments?
Did they mobilize the entire society to
prevent its spread to other places.
In January 2010, the New York Times commented
“America’s reaction was apt and lucky”.
Why "lucky”?
Because the death rate was at 0.02%,
killing a small number of people.
Because the United States had strong medical and research systems,
they were able to keep the death rate low
for the 60 million infected Americans.
However, there were no compulsory measures
to prevent the spread of the disease.
There were only travel warnings.
If we did this in Wuhan, no control over the virus carriers,
they would spread it to a larger population.
For countries with weak health systems or economies,
they did not have the capabilities to sustain and prevent an epidemic.
So they would not be as lucky as America in terms of death rate.
You mean, the United States did not define
the procedure to control the spread.
They could handle it domestically,
but they didn’t care about people travelling to
other countries and their local medical capabilities.
If you have lived in the West long enough, you would
know that they don’t have such mobilization abilities.
Engineers in China can leave on short notice,
but their western counterparts can't.
The Western systems are characterized
by having a complete procedure.
Generally, you don’t care as long as you have followed through the procedure.
- I have my contract.
- I'm on vacation.
Even the president can do so.
This is the “spirit of contract”.
Like the Australian Prime Minister could
go on vacation amid the bushfire crisis.
Yes, I often say that China is redefining modernization.
Modernization has to adapt to all kinds of new challenges.
The Western systems are facing a lot of them.
Just as WHO Director General said,
China is setting a new standard.
A new type of benchmark.
Why did Tedros Adhanom stand up and speak for China
when questioned by the western media about Wuhan’s lockdown?
It is because the experts deeply feel that China has
done more than its share in epidemic control.
As you can see, it is currently impossible for countries
like Japan and Singapore to do the same.
Their current reactions are basically the same:
Form an emergency team involving various ministers,
prepare funding, supplies, and masks, then wait for it to spread.
The health departments are prepared for intensive care.
They did so based on Wuhan’s experience.
The Internet says “China had a closed-book exam
while they had an open-book exam and still failed.”
The coronavirus is a completely new challenge for
any individual, any organization, and any government.
The international community made some very positive comments about China,
but some Western media are stigmatizing China
which affected people’s understanding of
the Chinese people and Chinese culture.
We have an audience who is an international student
in New York, Dai Yuxiao,
and we will connect with him and hear his questions.
- Hello, Yuxiao.
- Hello.
Hello. I learned you’ve been closely following
the updates of the coronavirus at home.
I would like to know how things are going for you,
and what your question is.
Recently on social media and in our daily life, many
people in the US or Europe are saying “Go back to China.”
Some even said “All Chinese people should die”.
A hate attack happened two weeks ago here in New York City.
A Chinese student was pushed onto subway tracks
because she was wearing a mask.
We've learned in the past that the US could not respond
to [natural] disasters better than China,
but the Americans are still blaming and only blaming China.
So my question is, facing the current situation,
what can the Chinese expats and emigrants do
to change their Western-centrism perspectives,
their stigmatization and discrimination?
How can we make them see China as it is?
That's my question.
Thank you, Yuxiao.
The Chinese communities abroad have felt
the pressure and stigmatization.
Professor Zhang, what do you think?
Actually, racism, cultural biases against China, and
ideological prejudice have always been there.
But now the outbreaks offered them a
new chance to “kick us when we’re down.”
To answer this question, we must first see that the problem has always been there,
and has just become more prominent now.
However, I noticed people who are
inflaming racism and cultural prejudice
have also been widely criticized within western societies,
even more strongly than the past
as these people are trampling on the bottom line of humanity.
Second, don't worry too much.
The epidemic will be over soon.
I’m aware that many foreigners have been
shocked by the China Model for the first time.
1.4 billion people put on masks all together and
stay at home to go through this difficult time.
Our nurses, PLA soldiers, and medical workers rushed to
the front line one batch after another.
This is unimaginable in the West.
We could see the examples we mentioned earlier
that the United States did terribly in the past.
For example, Hurricane Katrina in 2005.
If we give them some time, they will understand China better.
It’s a gradual process to understand
China and deepen their understanding.
Yuxiao’s question is probably one that
many Chinese students abroad also have.
But what if we are just trying to talk sense into people unreasonable?
Protect yourselves.
One big problem in the West is that in the past 20 years,
the actual income of most people did not increase,
and the rich-poor divide has widened.
Many people are angry, not only because of China.
Take the US an example, one year since
President Trump took office,
hate crimes concerning race, ethnicity, and cultures increased by 17%.
I would not say "they have filled the firewood to burn us”,
but the hate has a solid foundation.
We can make ourselves clear to reasonable people.
I believe there are many reasonable people
in the West and they can be our allies.
An infodemic usually follows an epidemic.
The Wall Street Journal's article “China Is the
Real Sick Man of Asia" has been very controversial.
A professor at China Health Policy and Management Society
wrote to the Wall Street Journal to refute the article.
I think, in addition to what Prof. Zhang said "protect yourselves”,
all the professionals can publish professional opinions to refute misinformation.
Preventing the spread of the infodemic
will help the prevention the epidemic.
We said this coronavirus is new,
and it’s a gradual process to understand it.
This also poses a huge challenge to our public health system.
I believe we all have our observations as the epidemic evolves.
in terms of how the public health system should improve.
Professor Cai, you are an expert in public health.
We’d like to hear your opinion on how our health systems should improve.
There are many buzzwords on the Internet about this
epidemic, such as “the black swan” and “the gray rhino”.
There are many external reasons.
First, the rapid growth of China has condensed
centuries into a short period of time.
This has increased China's socioeconomic complexity
and the difficulty to take control.
Second, when we focus on economic growth,
we sometimes overlooked public services.
Third, I'll read what Tedros Adhanom said,
"For too long, the world has operated
on a cycle of panic and neglect."
"We throw money at an outbreak, and when it’s over,
we forget about it and do nothing to prevent the next one."
He said this at a conference in Munich on February 15th,
and this is human nature.
SARS broke out, evolved, and ended.
Everyone recognized the importance of a good public health system and started building a network.
But after 17 years, some problems have emerged
such as “strong treatment and weak prevention”.
Because for the government, you can see how many cases
have been treated, how many lives have been saved;
but you cannot see how many cases have been prevented.
And the more you prevent, fewer will
happen and the less you will see.
Fourth, my data shows that in 2012, if 15 graduates were
employed by a disease control center in Shanghai,
about two-thirds of them would leave in 5 years.
Attraction to talent has declined due to
shrinking funding and lowering government priority.
An external and internal reason is that
acute infectious diseases used to be very severe
China had Influenza A, mouse plague, and schistosomiasis.
But as our living standards improves, we are mainly
facing chronic diseases such as cancer,
which means public health has taken on a different role.
So we have become forgetful, as Tedros Adhanom said.
We mainly worry about cancer now.
All these reasons combined can explain why we were
caught off guard by the sudden outbreak of the epidemic.
What Professor Cai just said makes a lot of sense.
As public health focuses on prevention, it’s like
“You raise an army for a thousand days but use it just for one.”
The one day at war is important, but a lot of research
can be done into how we "raise the army".
This time, we also learned that we should not be blindly
extensive like our SARS response, and we must be precise.
We need to calculate how many people we need
for the safety nets at community levels,
and equip communities with
competent personnel and adequate support.
Otherwise, we will be caught unprepared by a disaster.
Although the epidemic is still evolving, we have seen
data showing that things are changing for the good.
Different views can be discussed and debated.
We are not at all afraid of competition.
China, be confident.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
What else do you want to add about the development of
the coronavirus and our response?
I would like to add that, like the Russian scholar
[Sergey Alexandrovich] Markov said,
we endured great loss and sacrifice as a country,
but I believe the world will acknowledge that.
I am hopeful when we’ve won the war against the coronavirus,
China's path and model will gain higher
prestige and influence in the world,
and China will have more friends.
Just like how China and Southeast Asian countries bonded
after our response to the 1997 Asian financial crisis,
this is the outlook on justice and benefits that we uphold.
We are responsible.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
COVID-19 is new and it takes time to understand it.
Now that we have studied it and observed its development,
we must finally defeat it!
As the epidemic evolves, our show
will continue to focus on this topic.
Thank you both for coming.